      {
        questionText: 'A 72-year-old man comes to the physician for a health maintenance examination. He has no personal or family history of major medical illnesses. He has never smoked cigarettes. Pulse oximetry on room air shows an oxygen saturation of 98%. Physical examination shows plethoric skin and splenomegaly. Laboratory studies show: Hemoglobin 21.1 g/dL Hematocrit 61% Leukocyte count 15,000/mm3 Segmented neutrophils 68% Basophils 4% Lymphocytes 28% Platelet count 501,000/mm3 Leukocyte alkaline phosphatase increased A peripheral blood smear shows occasional giant platelets. The primary hematologic defect in this patient most likely occurred in which of the following cells?',
        options: [
          'Erythroid progenitor',
          'Hematopoietic stem',
          'Lymphatic progenitor',
          'Megakaryocyte progenitor',
          'Pluripotent stem'
        ],
        correctOptionIndex: 1
      },

      {
        questionText: 'A 3800-g (8-lb 6-oz) newborn is delivered vaginally at 39 weeks\' gestation after an uncomplicated pregnancy. Apgar scores are 9 and 9 at 1 and 5 minutes, respectively. The newborn is crying, has pink skin, and appears vigorous. Physical examination shows a vagina and also a structure that appears to be a penis, with the urethra located at the base near the opening of the vagina. Chromosomal analysis is ordered. Which of the following is the most likely cause of the intersex findings in this newborn if the karyotype is found to be 46,XX?',
        options: [
          '17?-Hydroxyprogesterone deficiency',
          'Increased concentration of m∩┐╜llerian-inhibiting substance',
          'Maternal androgen exposure',
          'Presence of the sex-determining region Y gene',
          '5?-Reductase deficiency'
        ],
        correctOptionIndex: 2
      },

      {
        questionText: 'An 80-year-old woman is brought to the emergency department (ED) 30 minutes after she fell out of her wheelchair at home. This is the second visit to the ED for a fall during the past 3 months. She lives with her daughter and son-in-law, who say they ∩┐╜do the best we can.∩┐╜ The patient has dementia, Alzheimer type, coronary artery disease, type 2 diabetes mellitus, and hypertension. Current medications are amlodipine, aspirin, atorvastatin, donepezil, long-acting insulin, and lisinopril. Five years ago, she underwent bilateral below-the-knee amputations because of infected ulcers of the feet. She uses a wheelchair for ambulation. Ten years ago, she underwent three-vessel coronary artery bypass grafting. She has smoked one-half pack of cigarettes daily for 60 years. She drinks one shot of whiskey nightly. She is thin and appears ill and disheveled. Her temperature is 37.2∩┐╜C (99.0∩┐╜F), pulse is 80/min, respirations are 20/min, and blood pressure is 120/80 mm Hg. Pulse oximetry on 2 L/min of oxygen by nasal cannula shows an oxygen saturation of 95%. Physical examination shows temporal wasting. There are scattered ecchymoses over the abdomen and all extremities. No other abnormalities are noted. Which of the following is the most appropriate initial history to obtain from this patient?',
        options: [
          'Abnormal bleeding',
          'Diet',
          'Relationship with her family',
          'Respiratory symptoms',
          'Urinary symptoms'
        ],
        correctOptionIndex: 2
      },

      {
        questionText: 'A 25-year-old woman comes to the physician because of a long history of pain with menses. The pain occurs on the first day of her 5-day menstrual period and lasts all day. She rates the pain as 10 on a 10-point scale. The most appropriate initial pharmacotherapy to relieve this patient\'s pain has which of the following mechanisms of action?',
        options: [
          'Inhibition of estrogen synthesis',
          'Inhibition of 11?-hydroxylase activity',
          'Inhibition of prostaglandin synthesis',
          'Stimulation of follicle-stimulating hormone synthesis',
          'Stimulation of luteinizing hormone synthesis'
        ],
        correctOptionIndex: 2
      },

      {
        questionText: 'A randomized clinical trial is conducted to compare wound healing and cosmetic differences between two surgical procedures for closing skin wounds following cesarean delivery. A total of 1000 women undergoing cesarean delivery during a 6-month period are enrolled in the study, which was 85% of the total number of patients undergoing the procedure. The results show a wound infection rate of 12 cases per 1000 women for Procedure A and 18 cases per 1000 women for Procedure B. Which of the following is the best estimate of the absolute risk reduction for wound infection following Procedure A compared with Procedure B?',
        options: [
          '(18/1000) ∩┐╜ (12/1000)',
          '0.85 ∩┐╜ (12/1000)',
          '0.85 ∩┐╜ (18/1000)',
          '[0.85 ∩┐╜ (18/1000∩┐╜12/1000)]',
          '[(1.2/100) ∩┐╜ (1.8/100)]/(1.8/100)'
        ],
        correctOptionIndex: 0
      },

      {
        questionText: 'A 58-year-old man with chronic obstructive pulmonary disease comes to the clinic with his wife for a follow-up examination. He has smoked one pack of cigarettes daily for 35 years. He has tried to quit smoking twice but was unsuccessful both times. At today∩┐╜s visit, when the physician asks the patient about smoking cessation, he says he is not ready to do so. The patient∩┐╜s wife states her husband∩┐╜s smoking makes her cough and gives her chest tightness. Which of the following is the most appropriate physician statement?',
        options: [
          '"Are there any reasons why you might want to quit smoking?"',
          '"Are you aware that your lung condition is chronic at this point?"',
          '"I\'m sure you don\'t want your wife to suffer as a result of your smoking." (D) "The majority of your health issues would improve if you quit smoking." (E) "Why haven\'t you been able to stay off cigarettes?"'
        ],
        correctOptionIndex: 0
      },

      {
        questionText: 'Seven days after admission to the psychiatric unit for treatment of eating disorders, a hospitalized 20-year-old woman has a 2-day history of moderate mouth pain on the inside of both cheeks. She also reports feeling "worthless and fat." Fluoxetine was started on admission. She appears distressed. She is 170 cm (5 ft 7 in) tall and weighs 77 kg (170 lb); BMI is 27 kg/m2. Vital signs are within normal limits. Physical examination shows bilateral swelling of the parotid and submandibular glands, discoloration of several teeth, and scarring on the dorsum of the right hand. Mental status examination shows no suicidal ideation or intent. Results of laboratory studies are within the reference ranges. A medication with which of the following mechanisms of action is most appropriate to treat this patient\'s current symptoms?',
        options: [
          'Binding to muscarinic acetylcholine receptors',
          'Binding to nicotinic acetylcholine receptors',
          'Inhibition of protein synthesis via binding to 50S ribosomal subunits and preventing peptide bond formation (D) Inhibition of protein synthesis via loss of DNA helical structure',
          'Interference with bacterial wall synthesis'
        ],
        correctOptionIndex: 0
      },

      {
        questionText: 'A 35-year-old woman, gravida 2, para 1, at 15 weeks∩┐╜ gestation is brought to the hospital in active labor. The physician care team confers and determines that the birth cannot be prevented and that the fetus will not survive. After explaining this fact to the patient, the patient says, "I know it is a long shot, but I still want my baby resuscitated and everything done to save him." After empathizing with the patient, which of the following is the most appropriate initial response by the physician?',
        options: [
          '"I will ask for a second opinion."',
          '"I will call the father of the baby to get his opinion as well."',
          '"I will call for a medical ethics consultation." (D) "I will do everything I can to save the baby."',
          '"I∩┐╜m very sorry, but the baby will not survive."'
        ],
        correctOptionIndex: 4
      },

      {
        questionText: 'A 48-year-old man who is a contractor interpreter working for the military at a US outpost in Afghanistan comes to the medical clinic because of a 20-day history of nonhealing, painless ulcers on his neck and arms. The lesions enlarged over time and began to express clear fluid, eventually forming shallow ulcers. When the symptoms began, he was sleeping on a mattress on the floor in an old building without air conditioning where the ambient temperature ranged from 21.1∩┐╜C (70.0∩┐╜F) to 43.3∩┐╜C (110.0∩┐╜F). He originally attributed the lesions to bug bites. Vital signs are within normal limits. Physical examination shows six 2-cm, papular lesions scattered over the neck and upper extremities; each lesion has a 0.6-cm ulcer in the center. There is no pus or exudate. Which of the following vectors is the most likely source of the lesions in this patient?',
        options: [
          'Flea',
          'Mosquito',
          'Sand fly',
          'Spider',
          'Tick'
        ],
        correctOptionIndex: 2
      },

      {
        questionText: 'A 17-year-old boy is brought to the clinic for a follow-up examination. He has been evaluated for three episodes of fullbody weakness at the ages of 13, 16, and 17 years. Each episode occurred when he lay down after playing in a football scrimmage. The weakness improved spontaneously during the next 6 hours; he was asymptomatic by the time he was evaluated by medical personnel. The patient attributes the episodes to eating "a lot of pasta and salty foods" prior to playing football. Results of a complete blood count and comprehensive metabolic profile following each episode have been within the reference ranges. He has no history of serious illness and takes no medications. Vital signs are within normal limits. Physical and neurologic examinations disclose no abnormalities. Which of the following serum concentrations is most likely to be abnormal if measured during one of this patient\'s episodes?',
        options: [
          'Calcium',
          'Chloride',
          'Magnesium',
          'Potassium',
          'Sodium'
        ],
        correctOptionIndex: 3
      },

      {
        questionText: 'A 3-day-old female newborn is brought to the hospital because of a yellowish, milky fluid leaking from both nipples. She was delivered at term to a 20-year-old woman. Pregnancy and delivery were uncomplicated. Examination of the newborn is otherwise unremarkable. Which of the following hormones is the most likely cause of this finding?',
        options: [
          'Maternal estrogen',
          'Maternal progesterone',
          'Maternal prolactin',
          'Newborn estrogen',
          'Newborn progesterone',
          'Newborn prolactin'
        ],
        correctOptionIndex: 2
      },

      {
        questionText: 'A 37-year-old man who is a carpenter is brought to the emergency department 45 minutes after the sudden onset of fever, shortness of breath, and palpitations. Four days ago, he sustained a puncture wound to his left hand; he treated the wound with antibacterial cream and a bandage. His temperature is 39∩┐╜C (102.2∩┐╜F), pulse is 120/min, respirations are 28/min, and blood pressure is 100/60 mm Hg. Examination of the left hand shows diffuse swelling, erythema, and a 2-cm, necrotic puncture wound. His leukocyte count is 14,000/mm3. Arterial blood gas analysis on room air shows a PCO2 of less than 32 mm Hg. Which of the following is the most likely infectious agent in this patient?',
        options: [
          'Clostridium tetani',
          'Mycobacterium abscessus',
          'Pasteurella multocida',
          'Pseudomonas aeruginosa',
          'Staphylococcus aureus USMLE STEP 1 SAMPLE TEST QUESTIONS BLOCK 3, ITEMS 81-119'
        ],
        correctOptionIndex: 4
      },

      {
        questionText: 'A 45-year-old woman comes to the office for a follow-up examination 2 weeks after she sustained a vertebral fracture at L1. The fracture occurred spontaneously and there is no history of trauma to the area or other fractures. She gained 27 kg (60 lb) during the 6 months before the fracture occurred. Her only medication is hydromorphone as needed for pain. She is 163 cm (5 ft 4 in) tall and now weighs 100 kg (220 lb); BMI is 38 kg/m2. Temperature is 37.0∩┐╜C (98.6∩┐╜F), pulse is 86/min, respirations are 12/min, and blood pressure is 145/98 mm Hg. Physical examination shows central obesity and purple striae over the abdomen bilaterally. The lower extremities appear thin. Results of laboratory studies are shown: Plasma Renin activity 5.0 ng/mL/h (N=0.6∩┐╜4.0) Metanephrine 0.3 nmol/L (N<0.4) Serum Cortisol, random 43 ?g/dL Adrenocorticotropic hormone 120 pg/mL (N<120) Aldosterone 8 ng/dL (N=2∩┐╜9) Urine 24-hour free cortisol excretion 340 ∩┐╜g/24 h (N=3.5∩┐╜45) The most likely cause of the fracture in this patient is an increase in which of the following processes?',
        options: [
          'Calcium absorption',
          'Calcium excretion',
          'Osteoblast proliferation',
          'Osteoclast proliferation',
          'Phosphorus absorption',
          'Phosphorus excretion'
        ],
        correctOptionIndex: 3
      },

      {
        questionText: 'A 25-year-old woman comes to the emergency department because of a 3-hour history of fever, severe headache, lightheadedness, dizziness, shaking chills, and muscle aches. Five hours ago, she was diagnosed with Lyme disease and began doxycycline therapy. She has no other history of serious illness and takes no other medications. Menses occur at regular 28-day intervals. She is currently menstruating and using a tampon. She appears anxious. Temperature is 37.0∩┐╜C (98.6∩┐╜F), pulse is 120/min, respirations are 30/min, and blood pressure is 90/60 mm Hg. Pulse oximetry on room air shows an oxygen saturation of 94%. Physical examination shows flushing and diaphoresis. Cardiopulmonary examination shows no other abnormalities. Which of the following is the most likely mechanism of this patient∩┐╜s current condition?',
        options: [
          'Exacerbation of infection by Borrelia burgdorferi',
          'Infection-mediated sepsis',
          'IgE-mediated allergic reaction to doxycycline',
          'Release of bacterial products producing acute inflammation (E) Secretion of bacterial endotoxins'
        ],
        correctOptionIndex: 3
      },

      {
        questionText: 'A newborn delivered at 36 weeks\' gestation to a 22-year-old woman, gravida 1, para 1, has difficulty feeding and listlessness. The mother received no prenatal care. Spontaneous vaginal delivery was uncomplicated. The mother\'s only medication was a prenatal vitamin. The newborn\'s length is 49 cm (19 in; 39th percentile), and weight is 3100 g (6 lb 13 oz; 30th percentile); head circumference is 33 cm (13 in; 12th percentile). Temperature is 37.0∩┐╜C (98.6∩┐╜F), pulse is 134/min, respirations are 38/min, and blood pressure is 73/50 mm Hg. Physical examination shows ambiguous genitalia. Results of serum studies are shown: Na+ 133 mEq/L K+ 5.0 mEq/L (N=3.2∩┐╜5.5) Cl∩┐╜ 103 mEq/L HCO3∩┐╜ 17 mEq/L Glucose 42 mg/dL (N=30∩┐╜60) The most appropriate pharmacotherapy for this patient targets which of the following receptors?',
        options: [
          'Adrenocorticotropic hormone',
          'Aldosterone',
          'Androgen',
          'Gonadotropin-releasing hormone',
          'Growth hormone'
        ],
        correctOptionIndex: 1
      },

      {
        questionText: 'A 60-year-old woman is brought to the emergency department because of a 4-day history of fever, joint aches, and rash. Three weeks ago, she was admitted to the hospital for treatment of Staphylococcal aureus endocarditis. She has received 21 days out of a prescribed 42-day course of intravenous oxacillin. Currently, she appears to be in mild distress. Temperature is 38.0∩┐╜C (100.4∩┐╜F), pulse is 115/min, respirations are 24/min, and blood pressure is 120/70 mm Hg. Pulse oximetry on room air shows an oxygen saturation of 97%. Physical examination shows a diffuse maculopapular rash over the trunk and upper and lower extremities. There is no pus or erythema at the skin insertion site of the peripherally inserted central catheter line initially placed on the day of hospital discharge. Results of laboratory studies are shown: Hemoglobin 11.1 g/dL Hematocrit 33% Leukocyte count 12,100/mm3 Segmented neutrophils 78% Eosinophils 9% Lymphocytes 7% Monocytes 6% Platelet count 341,000/mm3 Serum Na+ 133 mEq/L K+ 6.5 mEq/L Cl? 100 mEq/L HCO3? 15 mEq/L Urea nitrogen 65 mg/dL Glucose 96 mg/dL Creatinine 5.7 mg/dL Urine microscopy shows eosinophils and WBC casts. Which of the following is the most likely underlying cause of this patient\'s condition?',
        options: [
          'Collapsing focal segmental glomerulosclerosis',
          'Glomerular hypertrophy with hemorrhage and necrosis',
          'Interstitial inflammatory infiltrate',
          'Mesangial expansion with glomerular basement membrane thickening (E) Proximal tubular dilation with loss of brush border'
        ],
        correctOptionIndex: 2
      },

      {
        questionText: 'A 48-year-old man comes to the physician requesting treatment for alcohol withdrawal. He reports a 30-year history of consuming 6 to 10 beers daily. He has had two citations for driving while intoxicated. He has previously experienced alcohol-associated seizures and withdrawal symptoms. His vital signs are within normal limits. Physical examination shows palmar erythema. The most appropriate pharmacotherapy in this patient most likely has which of the following mechanisms?',
        options: [
          'Blockade of dopamine receptors',
          'Decreased activity of dopamine transporters',
          'Enhancement of the effect of postsynaptic ?-aminobutyric acid (GABA)',
          'Increased GABA transaminase activity',
          'Inhibition of glutamate release',
          'Inhibition of serotonin reuptake',
          'Opening of glutamate channels',
          'Stimulation of 5-hydroxytryptophan receptors'
        ],
        correctOptionIndex: 2
      },

      {
        questionText: 'A 6-year-old girl is brought to the office because of two episodes of vaginal bleeding during the past 2 months. She has no history of serious illness and receives no medications. She does not appear to be in distress. She is at the 60th percentile for height, 40th percentile for weight, and 35th percentile for BMI. Vital signs are within normal limits. Physical examination discloses palpable breast buds and minimal coarse, pigmented hair on the labia. The remainder of the examination shows no abnormalities. Results of serum studies are shown: Thyroid-stimulating hormone 2.1 mU/mL (N=0.5∩┐╜5.0) Testosterone 680 ng/dL (N=0.17∩┐╜0.7) Adrenocorticotropic hormone 18 pg/mL (N=9∩┐╜52) Estradiol 185 pg/mL (N<20) Follicle-stimulating hormone 15 mIU/mL (N<6.7) Luteinizing hormone 3.0 mIU/mL (N<0.2) Which of the following is the most likely cause of this patient\'s condition?',
        options: [
          'Central activation of neurons',
          'Ectopic prolactin secretion',
          'Exogenous sex steroid secretion',
          'Germline GNAS activating mutation',
          '21-Hydroxylase deficiency'
        ],
        correctOptionIndex: 0
      },

      {
        questionText: 'A previously healthy 64-year-old man is brought to the emergency department 3 hours after the sudden onset of severe flank pain. He has no history of similar pain or serious illness. He takes no medications. He appears to be in distress. His pulse is 100/min, and blood pressure is 168/92 mm Hg. Physical examination shows a soft abdomen with left-sided tenderness. Urinalysis shows microscopic hematuria. A CT scan of the abdomen shows a small ureteric calculus. Analgesic therapy is initiated and the pain resolves 1 hour later. The urine is then strained and a uric acid calculus is found. Which of the following processes is most likely impaired in this patient?',
        options: [
          'Bile salt metabolism',
          'Cholesterol metabolism',
          'Cytochrome P450 activity',
          'Purine metabolism',
          'Urea cycle'
        ],
        correctOptionIndex: 3
      },

      {
        questionText: 'Patient Information Age: 34 years Gender: M, self-identified Race/Ethnicity: unspecified Site of Care: office The patient presents because of a 2-year history of recurrent abdominal pain and diarrhea; he also has had an 11-kg (25lb) weight loss during this period. He describes his stools as copious, loose, oily and foul-smelling. His bowel movements occur six to eight times daily, often immediately after meals, and are associated with bloating and cramping. Since the age of 21 years, he has had several episodes of acute pancreatitis. He has not had fevers or bloody stools. He is 178 cm (5 ft 10 in) tall and weighs 57 kg (125 lb); BMI is 18 kg/m2. Physical examination shows a flat abdomen with hyperactive bowel sounds and diffuse mild tenderness. Digital rectal examination shows no abnormalities. Test of the stool for occult blood is negative. Treatment with which of the following enzymes is most likely to be beneficial in this patient?',
        options: [
          'Amylase',
          'Lactase',
          'Lipase',
          'Protease',
          'Tryptase'
        ],
        correctOptionIndex: 2
      },

      {
        questionText: 'A 4-year-old girl with type 1 diabetes mellitus is brought to the emergency department by her father because of a 4-hour episode of restlessness, sweating, and confusion that occurred during the night. Yesterday, he allowed her to eat cupcakes and cotton candy at a county fair. At her bedtime that evening, he increased her dose of subcutaneous intermediateacting and long-acting insulin. Her symptoms began 6 hours later, then resolved spontaneously. After being informed this morning of this nighttime episode, the mother insisted the father bring the patient to the hospital. On arrival, the patient is alert. Her vital signs are within normal limits. Examination shows no abnormalities. Her fingerstick blood glucose concentration is 72 mg/dL. Urinalysis is negative for glucose and ketones. Which of the following is the most likely explanation for this patient\'s nighttime symptoms?',
        options: [
          'Hyperglycemia caused by increased glucose consumption',
          'Hyperglycemia caused by increased glycogen metabolism',
          'Hyperglycemia caused by insufficient exogenous insulin',
          'Hypoglycemia caused by excess exogenous insulin',
          'Hypoglycemia caused by excessive renal glucose loss',
          'Hypoglycemia caused by increased glucagon secretion',
          'Nightmare disorder',
          'Sleep terror disorder'
        ],
        correctOptionIndex: 3
      },

      {
        questionText: 'A 66-year-old man who was recently diagnosed with Parkinson disease comes to the physician for a follow-up examination. Carbidopa-levodopa therapy was initiated at the time of diagnosis. The patient tells the physician that he still has episodes during which he "freezes." He has a clumsy gait, and there is rigidity of his upper extremities and hands. An adjunct therapy designed to inhibit which of the following enzymes is most likely indicated in this patient?',
        options: [
          'Aromatic L-amino acid decarboxylase',
          'Dopamine ?-hydroxylase',
          'Monoamine oxidase B',
          'Phenylethanolamine N-methyltransferase',
          'Tyrosine hydroxylase'
        ],
        correctOptionIndex: 2
      },

      {
        questionText: 'A 2-week-old male newborn is brought to the office for a well-child examination. He was delivered following an uncomplicated, spontaneous vaginal delivery at 41 weeks\' gestation. The mother has no history of serious illness and did not receive prenatal care. Her only medication is a prenatal vitamin. She has consumed large amounts of vodka nightly for 10 years. Which of the following examination findings is most likely to be present in this patient?',
        options: [
          'Hypospadias',
          'Limb hypoplasia',
          'Neck webbing',
          'Short palpebral fissures',
          'Spasticity'
        ],
        correctOptionIndex: 3
      },

      {
        questionText: 'Patient Information Age: 16 years Gender: M, self-identified Race/Ethnicity: Hispanic, self-identified Site of Care: clinic History Reason for Visit/Chief Concern: "I haven\'t started puberty yet." History of Present Illness: ∩┐╜ absence of pubic and facial hair ∩┐╜ small penis and testicle size Past Medical History: ∩┐╜ no serious illness Medications: ∩┐╜ none Allergies: ∩┐╜ no known drug allergies Psychosocial History: ∩┐╜ does not smoke cigarettes, drink alcoholic beverages, or use other substances Physical Examination Temp Pulse Resp BP O2 Sat Ht Wt BMI 36.0∩┐╜C 76/min 13/min 108/61 mm Hg 98% 184 cm 90 kg 27 kg/m2 (96.8∩┐╜F) on RA (6 ft) (198 lb) 90th %ile 97th %ile ∩┐╜ Appearance: long extremities ∩┐╜ Skin: no facial or axillary hair ∩┐╜ HEENT: PERRLA ∩┐╜ Chest: bilateral gynecomastia ∩┐╜ Pulmonary: clear to auscultation ∩┐╜ Cardiac: normal S1 and S2 ∩┐╜ Abdominal: normoactive bowel sounds; no tenderness to palpation; no hepatosplenomegaly ∩┐╜ Genitourinary: small testicular and penile size; minimal pubic hair; SMR 2 ∩┐╜ Neurologic: muscle strength 5/5 throughout Diagnostic Studies: Serum Follicle-stimulating hormone 45 mIU/mL Luteinizing hormone 34 mIU/mL Testosterone 45 ng/dL (N=270∩┐╜950) TSH 2.2 ?U/L 94th %ile Question: Which of the following is the most likely underlying cause of this patient\'s condition?',
        options: [
          'Constitutional delay in puberty',
          'Hypoplasia of hypothalamic gonadotropin-releasing hormone neurons',
          'Inactivating mutation of the follicle-stimulating hormone-receptor',
          'Mutation in the 21-hydroxylase gene',
          'Nondisjunction of X chromosome during meiosis'
        ],
        correctOptionIndex: 4
      },

      {
        questionText: 'A 15-year-old boy is brought to the office by his parents to discuss results of a biopsy done 3 days ago for a rapidly enlarging neck mass. He first noted the mass 1 month ago. Two weeks ago, he was evaluated for an episode of prolonged epistaxis and was found to have a right ear effusion, which was treated with amoxicillin-clavulanic acid. He has no other history of serious illness and takes no medications. Height is at the 10th percentile, weight is at the 50th percentile, and BMI is at the 75th percentile. Vital signs are within normal limits. Physical examination shows a right ear effusion and a 4-cm, firm mass in the right posterior triangle of the neck. Results of a biopsy specimen show squamous epithelium with indistinct cell margins, enlarged atypical nuclei, and absent keratin formation. Which of the following infectious agents is the most likely underlying cause of this patient\'s current condition?',
        options: [
          'Cytomegalovirus',
          'Epstein-Barr virus',
          'HIV',
          'Human herpesvirus 8'
        ],
        correctOptionIndex: 1
      },

      {
        questionText: 'A 48-year-old woman with type 2 diabetes mellitus comes to the physician for a follow-up examination. Current medications are metformin and once-daily insulin. She travels frequently and works long hours. She says that her meals are usually fast food. She leads a sedentary lifestyle. She often forgets to measure her blood glucose concentration. Her last hemoglobin A1c was measured as 8.4%. Which of the following is the most appropriate action by the physician to help this patient improve her diabetic control?',
        options: [
          'Create an exercise regimen for the patient',
          'Explore barriers to diet adherence',
          'Increase the patient\'s insulin dosage',
          'Increase the patient\'s metformin dosage',
          'Measure the patient\'s blood glucose concentration',
          'Order measurement of the patient\'s microalbumin concentration (G) Refer the patient to a nutritionist'
        ],
        correctOptionIndex: 1
      },

      {
        questionText: 'A 74-year-old woman with a history of coronary artery disease is brought to the emergency department 30 minutes after the sudden onset of crushing chest pain. Her pulse is 120/min, and systolic blood pressure is 70 mm Hg. An ECG shows sinus rhythm with ST elevation in leads V1 through V3. The physician plans to administer a drug to increase the patient\'s blood pressure without increasing her pulse. Which of the following drugs is most appropriate for this patient?',
        options: [
          'Dopamine',
          'Epinephrine',
          'Isoproterenol',
          'Norepinephrine',
          'Phenylephrine'
        ],
        correctOptionIndex: 4
      },

      {
        questionText: 'A 2-month-old girl is admitted to the hospital because of severe pneumonia. She has a history of mucocutaneous candidiasis and chronic diarrhea. Her pulse is 160/min, and respirations are 40/min. Crackles are heard over both lung fields. Her leukocyte count is 5400/mm3 (N=5000∩┐╜19,500), with 86% segmented neutrophils, 6% lymphocytes, and 8% monocytes. Immunologic testing of a specimen obtained via bronchoscopy is positive for Pneumocystis jirovecii. Flow cytometry shows normal concentrations of natural killer cells but no T or B lymphocytes in the peripheral blood. Results of a polymerase chain reaction test of the immunoglobulin V(D)J regions from a bone marrow specimen show an absence of characteristic rearrangements. The most likely cause of these findings is an alteration of which of the following?',
        options: [
          'Bruton tyrosine kinase',
          'CD40 ligand',
          'Mevalonate kinase',
          'NADPH oxidase',
          'Recombination-activating gene 1 (RAG1) and RAG2'
        ],
        correctOptionIndex: 4
      },

      {
        questionText: 'A 25-year-old woman, gravida 1, para 1, comes to the office because of a 2-week history of palpitations and heat intolerance. She delivered her child 3 months ago following an uncomplicated pregnancy and delivery. She is breastfeeding. She has no history of serious illness and takes no medications. She is 163 cm (5 ft 4 in) tall and weighs 54 kg (120 lb); BMI is 21 kg/m2. Temperature is 37∩┐╜C (98.6∩┐╜F), pulse is 106/min, respirations are 20/min, and blood pressure is 124/68 mm Hg. Examination shows moist palms and bilateral lid lag. No exophthalmos is noted. The thyroid gland is enlarged and nontender. No murmurs are heard on cardiac examination. Deep tendon reflexes are 3+. Serum studies show an undetectable TSH concentration, thyroxine (T4) concentration of 20 ?g/dL, and triiodothyronine (T3) concentration of 275 ng/dL. Which of the following is the most likely mechanism of this patient\'s symptoms?',
        options: [
          'Activation of mutations of TSH receptors',
          'Increased serum thyroglobulin concentration',
          'Ischemic injury to the hypothalamus',
          'Lymphocytic infiltration of the thyroid',
          'Presence of TSH receptor autoantibodies'
        ],
        correctOptionIndex: 3
      },

      {
        questionText: 'A 73-year-old woman comes to the emergency department because of a 6-hour history of severe abdominal pain. She has chronic atrial fibrillation and underwent placement of a prosthetic mitral valve 4 years ago. Her pulse is 120/min and irregularly irregular, and blood pressure is 80/60 mm Hg. Arteriography shows an embolus in the superior mesenteric artery lodged just beyond the patent middle colic artery. A laparotomy is done. During this procedure, which of the following segments of the abdominal viscera is most likely to appear normal?',
        options: [
          'Ascending colon',
          'Distal ileum',
          'Distal jejunum',
          'Proximal ileum',
          'Proximal jejunum'
        ],
        correctOptionIndex: 4
      },

      {
        questionText: 'A 2-year-old boy is brought to the physician because of failure to thrive. He also has had loose, fatty, foul-smelling stools and a cough during the past 2 weeks. He is at the 30th percentile for height and 10th percentile for weight. Physical examination shows no other abnormalities. Laboratory studies show steatorrhea and a sweat chloride concentration of 80 mmol/L. A chest x-ray shows hyperinflation. Sputum culture grows Haemophilus influenzae and Staphylococcus aureus. Secretion of which of the following substances is most likely to be decreased in this patient?',
        options: [
          'Bicarbonate',
          'Gastric acid',
          'Glucagon',
          'Insulin',
          'Intrinsic factor'
        ],
        correctOptionIndex: 0
      },

      {
        questionText: 'A 73-year-old man is brought to the emergency department by his family 1 hour after he walked into the left side of a door frame when leaving his bedroom and then tripped over a chair that was on his left side. Visual field testing shows left lower quadrantanopia. When tactile stimuli are presented on both the left and right sides simultaneously, the patient correctly identifies only the ones on the right. Further examination shows no motor or language deficits. Proprioception is intact. This patient most likely has a brain lesion in which of the following lobes?',
        options: [
          'Left frontal',
          'Left parietal',
          'Left temporal',
          'Right frontal',
          'Right parietal',
          'Right temporal'
        ],
        correctOptionIndex: 4
      },

      {
        questionText: 'A 10-year-old boy is brought to the physician because of a 3-week history of nosebleeds and easy bruisability. His older brother has had similar episodes. He is at the 30th percentile for height and weight. Physical examination shows nasal and gingival bleeding and several ecchymoses over the trunk and upper and lower extremities in various stages of healing. Laboratory studies show a platelet count of 300,000/mm3 (N=150,000∩┐╜400,000). Platelet adhesion testing shows a normal response to ristocetin, but aggregation does not occur in response to thrombin; platelet morphology is normal. Prothrombin time and activated partial thromboplastin time are within the reference ranges. A defect in which of the following is the most likely cause of the findings in this patient?',
        options: [
          'Factor VII (proconvertin)',
          'Fibrinogen',
          'Glycoprotein IIb-IIIa',
          'Granule storage pool',
          'von Willebrand factor'
        ],
        correctOptionIndex: 2
      },

      {
        questionText: 'A previously healthy 45-year-old woman who works as a park ranger comes to the physician because of a 1-week history of shortness of breath, even at rest. She has lived in the mountains at 10,000 feet above sea level for 2 years; the physician∩┐╜s office is located at sea level. Her pulse is 85/min, respirations are 18/min, and blood pressure is 125/90 mm Hg. Physical examination while sitting upright shows jugular venous distention and 2+ pedal edema. During the past 2 years, which of the following has most likely decreased in this patient?',
        options: [
          'Height of P waves in lead I of the patient\'s ECG',
          'Height of R waves in lead V1 of the patient\'s ECG',
          'Hematocrit',
          'Pulmonary vascular resistance',
          'Right ventricular diastolic compliance',
          'Right ventricular wall thickness'
        ],
        correctOptionIndex: 4
      },

      {
        questionText: 'A 5-year-old girl is brought to the office by her mother because of a 6-hour history of bloody diarrhea. She is interactive and in no acute distress. Her blood pressure is 90/55 mm Hg. Abdominal examination shows normoactive bowel sounds. Stool cultures are obtained, and the patient\'s mother is advised to give the girl plenty of fluids. Five days later, the patient develops decreased urine output and is brought back to the office. Her blood pressure is now 135/88 mm Hg. Physical examination shows pallor. Laboratory studies show: Hemoglobin 8.5 g/dL (N=11∩┐╜15) Hematocrit 26% (N=28%∩┐╜45%) Platelet count 45,000/mm3 (N=150,000∩┐╜400,000) Serum creatinine 3.3 mg/dL (N=0.3∩┐╜0.7) Which of the following infectious agents is the most likely cause of these findings?',
        options: [
          'Campylobacter jejuni',
          'Escherichia coli',
          'Rotavirus',
          'Salmonella enterica serovar enteritidis',
          'Yersinia pestis'
        ],
        correctOptionIndex: 1
      },

      {
        questionText: 'A 78-year-old woman is admitted to the intensive care unit because of diverticulitis complicated by Escherichia coli sepsis. Treatment with ciprofloxacin is started. Three days later, her serum creatinine concentration has increased from 0.7 mg/dL on admission to 1.3 mg/dL. Urinalysis shows muddy brown casts. The most likely cause of the findings in this patient is ischemia of which of the following structures?',
        options: [
          'Bowman capsule',
          'Glomerulus',
          'Interstitium',
          'Proximal tubule',
          'Renal vein'
        ],
        correctOptionIndex: 3
      },

      {
        questionText: 'A 19-year-old man who is a college freshman comes to the office because of a 4-day history of tender, swollen glands. He also has a 6-day history of fever, malaise, and decreased appetite. His temperature is 38.7∩┐╜C (101.7∩┐╜F). Physical examination shows swelling of the parotid glands. Which of the following infectious agents is the most likely cause of these findings?',
        options: [
          'Epstein-Barr virus',
          'Hepatitis B virus',
          'Measles virus',
          'Mumps virus',
          'Rubella virus'
        ],
        correctOptionIndex: 3
      },

      {
        questionText: 'A 34-year-old woman with myasthenia gravis comes to the emergency department because of a 2-day history of increasing weakness, shortness of breath, and abdominal cramping. Current medications are prednisone and pyridostigmine. Her temperature is 37∩┐╜C (98.6∩┐╜F), pulse is 45/min, and respirations are 25/min and shallow. Her voice is soft and hypernasal, and she coughs weakly when swallowing water. Breath and heart sounds are normal. Pulmonary testing shows inability to generate a normal negative inspiratory force during forced inspiration. The abdomen is soft and nontender, with increased bowel sounds. Muscle strength is 4/5 diffusely, with severe, continuous, and diffuse fasciculations. Deep tendon reflexes are sluggish, but symmetric. Which of the following is the most likely cause of this patient\'s weakness?',
        options: [
          'Aspiration pneumonia',
          'Guillain-Barr∩┐╜ syndrome',
          'Insufficient dose of prednisone',
          'Motor neuron disease',
          'Pyridostigmine overdose'
        ],
        correctOptionIndex: 4
      },

      {
        questionText: 'A 35-year-old woman comes to the office because she has had three first-trimester spontaneous abortions during the past 3 years. Physical examination shows no abnormalities. Laboratory studies show no endocrine abnormalities. Chromosomal analysis shows a paracentric inversion of the long arm of chromosome 1. Which of the following best describes this patient∩┐╜s risk for early spontaneous abortions and a liveborn child with aneuploidy? Risk for Early Risk for Liveborn Spontaneous Abortions Child With Aneuploidy',
        options: [
          'High high (B) High low (C) Low high',
          'Low low'
        ],
        correctOptionIndex: 1
      },

      {
        questionText: 'A 25-year-old man comes to the office because of a 4-hour history of irritability, restlessness, tremor, and palpitations. He is a known user of amphetamines. His pulse is 120/min, respirations are 25/min, and blood pressure is 150/100 mm Hg. Physical examination shows no abnormalities. The most likely cause of this patient\'s symptoms is sympathomimetic activity arising from which of the following?',
        options: [
          'Decreased intracellular metabolism of biogenic amines',
          'Decreased monoamine oxidase activity',
          'Decreased presynaptic receptor activation',
          'Increased intracellular metabolism of biogenic amines',
          'Increased presynaptic receptor activation',
          'Increased release of biogenic amines'
        ],
        correctOptionIndex: 5
      },

      {
        questionText: 'A 14-year-old boy is brought to the office by his mother because of a 1-week history of seizures and difficulty walking. Physical examination shows decreased sensation over the hands and feet and generalized weakness. He walks with an ataxic gait. A muscle biopsy specimen shows coarsely granular fibers that stain red with Gomori trichrome stain. This patient most likely has a genetic defect that most directly affects the synthesis of which of the following?',
        options: [
          'ATP',
          'Creatine phosphate',
          'Glycogen',
          'NADH',
          'Pyruvate'
        ],
        correctOptionIndex: 0
      },

      {
        questionText: 'A 72-year-old man is brought to the office because of a 6-month history of increasing fatigue and a 1-month history of numbness of his feet. Physical examination shows marked pallor. Proprioception and sensation to vibration are decreased in the lower extremities. Laboratory studies show: Hemoglobin 7.6 g/dL Mean corpuscular volume 117 ?m3 Reticulocyte count 0% Serum vitamin B12 (cobalamin) 23.6 pg/mL (N=200∩┐╜900) Histopathology of a gastric mucosal biopsy specimen shows atrophic gastritis with extensive lymphocyte infiltration. Serologic studies will most likely show autoantibodies to which of the following labeled cell types in the photomicrograph of normal mucosa or to one of its secretory products? atrial fibrillation. Appropriate pharmacotherapy was initiated at that time, and normal sinus rhythm was restored. Her pulse is 76/min, and blood pressure is 132/86 mm Hg. Physical examination shows no abnormalities. The ECGs shown represent before (solid line) and after (dashed line) administration of the antiarrhythmic drug. Which of the following drugs was most likely prescribed?',
        options: [
          'Amiodarone',
          'Digoxin',
          'Mexiletine',
          'Phenytoin',
          'Verapamil'
        ],
        correctOptionIndex: 4
      },

      {
        questionText: 'A 4-year-old boy develops fever 3 weeks after being admitted to the hospital for induction chemotherapy for treatment of acute lymphoblastic leukemia. Chemotherapy medications are L-asparaginase, dexamethasone, doxorubicin, and vincristine. His temperature is 38.2∩┐╜C (100.8∩┐╜F), pulse is 122/min, and respirations are 24/min. Physical examination shows pallor, alopecia, and ulcerations over the gums. A central venous catheter with entry site in the right upper chest is present but has no surrounding erythema. A blood culture grows gram-negative rods after 36 hours. Which of the following underlying mechanisms is the most likely cause of this patient\'s susceptibility to infection?',
        options: [
          'Deficiency of terminal complement',
          'Hypogammaglobulinemia',
          'Impaired T-lymphocyte function',
          'Inhibition of tumor necrosis factor ? function',
          'Neutropenia'
        ],
        correctOptionIndex: 4
      },

      {
        questionText: 'A 6-year-old boy with acute lymphoblastic leukemia is brought to the office for a follow-up examination. He is receiving high-dose methotrexate therapy. A drug is added to the patient\'s medication regimen to decrease the toxicity of this therapy to normal cells. The beneficial effect of this new drug on normal cells is most likely achieved by bypassing the cellular requirement for which of the following enzymes?',
        options: [
          'Dihydrofolate reductase',
          'Methionine synthase',
          'Pyruvate decarboxylase',
          'Thiamine pyrophosphate',
          'Thymidylate synthase'
        ],
        correctOptionIndex: 0
      },

      {
        questionText: 'A screening test for breast cancer is administered to 1000 women with biopsy-proven breast cancer and to 1000 women without breast cancer. The test results are positive for 250 of the subjects with breast cancer and 100 of the subjects without breast cancer. The screening test is now to be used on a population of 100,000 women with a known prevalence rate of breast cancer of 80 per 100,000. Which of the following is the expected number of false-positives?',
        options: [
          '20',
          '80',
          '8993',
          '9992',
          '10,012 ANSWER FORM FOR USMLE STEP 1 SAMPLE TEST QUESTIONS Block 1 (Questions 1∩┐╜40)'
        ],
        correctOptionIndex: 3
      }
